<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?> 
<cheatsheet title="Using the ICAT Explorer">

  <intro>
    <description>
      This cheat sheet describes how to use the ICAT explorer in order to navigate and display your ICAT data, including investigations, datasets and datafiles.
    </description>
  </intro>
  <item
        title="Creating an ICAT project">
     <description>
   In the project explorer, right click and select <b> New &gt; other &gt; ICAT Archive Project &gt; Create ICAT Project</b>
In the opened wizard, enter your fedid and password, and fill the other values or keep the default ones, then click the &apos;Finish&apos; button or press &apos;Enter&apos; on your keyboard.<br/><br/>
If the authentication is successful, an ICAT project will be created in the project explorer containing a list of all your visits registered within the ICAT database.<br/><br/>
Please note that an additional project with the same ICAT project name plus &apos;-downloadFiles&apos; will be created automatically. The latter will hold all downloaded datafiles. A datafile is downloaded to the local filesystem when the user double clicks on it.
     </description>
  </item>

<item
        title="Browsing your data">
     <description>
        The ICAT project provides a tree-based navigation of your data.<br/><br/>
		Nodes can be expanded to show their content.<br/><br/>
        A single click on an item (investigation, dataset or datafile) will update the metadata table with corresponding metadata from the ICAT database. Please open metadata view first.<br/><br/>
        A double click on a datafile will open it in the corresponding editor. 
     </description>
  </item>

   <item
        title="Drag-and-drop from ICAT project into eclipse">
     <description>
   
   
	You can select any combination of files and/or datasets from the ICAT Explorer for drag and drop into an eclipse project.<br/><br/>
	Since the transfer is from a remote server, this process can be time consuming and thus, is run as a separate job.<br/>
	Status of data transfer is shown in the progress monitor in the status bar of DAWN/SDA.<br/><br/>

	Once, all files have been copied, the Project Explorer is refreshed.<br/><br/>
	Please note that files can be copied to &apos;non-virtual&apos; folders targets only.<br/><br/>	
</description>
</item>

<item
       title="ICAT Connection configuration">
<description>
The plugin preferences page allows the configuration of the parameters used to create an ICAT connection.<br/>
This includes the wsdl url of the ICAT webservice, the sftp server used to download the files locally, etc.<br/><br/>
The sites configured in the preferences page (e.g. Diamond Light Source, ILL) are the ones that actually appear in the create connection wizard.<br/><br/>
The preferences page allows adding new ICAT sites by editing the different fields (wsdl url, etc).
  </description>
  </item>

<item
        title="ICAT project contextual menu and toolbar">
<description>
  Please note that a  user is automatically logged out from the ICAT after 2 hours of first login.<br/>
        Also, if the SDA is closed all ICAT connections will be closed.
        <br/><br/>
        In order to reconnect a disconnected ICAT, right-click the project and select &apos;Reconnect&apos;. Fill the needed information in the wizard and click &apos;Finish&apos;<br/><br/>
        The same contextual menu allows to sweep a disconnected project.<br/><br/>
The toolbar button &apos;sweep disconnected ICATs&apos; deletes all disconnected ICAT projects.<br/><br/>

The contextual menu also allows to refresh a connected ICAT project.<br/><br/>

</description>
</item>
</cheatsheet>
